Reading
Theme parks
Fun and more than fun
Which theme park would you like to visit?
There are various kinds of theme parks,
with a different park for almost everything:
food, culture, science, cartoons,
movies or history.
Some parks are famous for having the biggest or longest roller coasters,
others for showing the famous sights and sounds of a culture.
Whichever and whatever you like,
there is a theme park for you!
The theme park you are probably most familiar with is Disneyland.
It can be found in several parts of the world.
As you wander around the fantasy amusement park,
you may see Snow White or Mickey Mouse in a parade or on the street.
Of course Disneyland also has many exciting rides,
from giant swinging ships to terrifying free-fall drops.
With all these attractions,
no wonder tourism is increasing wherever there is a Disneyland.
If you want to have fun and more than fun,
come to Disneyland!
Dollywood, in the beautiful Smoky Mountains in the southeastern USA,
is one of the most unique theme parks in the world.
Dollywood shows and celebrates America's traditional southeastern culture.
Although Dollywood has rides, the park's main attraction is its culture.
People come from all over America to see carpenters and other craftsmen make wood,
glass and iron objects in the old-fashioned way.
Visit the candy shop to try the same kind of candy that American southerners made 150 years ago,
or take a ride on the only steam- engine train still working in the southeast USA.
You can even see beautiful bald eagles in the world's largest bald eagle preserve.
And for those who like rides,
Dollywood has one of the best old wooden roller coasters,
Thunderhead.
Come to Dollywood to have fun learning all about America's historical southeastern culture!
If you want to experience the ancient days and great deeds of English knights
and ladies, princes and queens,
then England's Camelot Park is the place for you.
Every area of the park is modelled after life in the days of King Arthur
and the Knights of the Round Table.
In one place, you can watch magic shows with Merlin the Wizard.
If you want to see fighting with swords or on horseback,
then the jousting area is a good place to visit.
If you do well there, King Arthur may choose you to fight in the big jousting tournament.
Do you like animals?
Then visit the farm area,
and learn how people in ancient England ran their farms
and took care of their animals.
To enter a world of fantasy about ancient England,
come to Camelot Park!